Robbie Mackay

Software Developer & Engineering Leader

+64 275762243 Auckland, New Zealand rm@robbiemackay.com

A thoughtful technical leader with over 10 years of experience building successful web applications, with a focus on nonprofits and companies that make the world a better place. I thrive in a passionate collaborative team, driven by users' needs and with freedom to make things better.

Experience

Private Chef Club – Lead Developer

2019 - Present. Remote

Private Chef Club is a food delivery startup, serving homestyle meals for families.

- Launched SMS and web ordering services with > 30% conversion rates from sign up to first order and 60% customer retention at 3 months.
- Automated delivery tasks and notifications to reduce manual errors and preparation time.
- Led user journey mapping to identify gaps and inform product roadmap.
- Implemented a minimal continuous delivery pipeline for fast, high quality releases, with increased visibility.
- Managed software development contractors to ensure code quality and on-time delivery.

Python, PostgreSQL, Javascript, Vue, Svelte, Redis, Celery, Heroku.

Ushahidi – CTO & Lead Developer

2015 - 2018. Remote

Ushahidi is an open-source crowdsourcing platform to collect, manage, visualize, and respond to data from marginalized people or people in crisis situations.

- Led a distributed team of 10 developers spread over 6 countries.
- Migrated from an end-of-life framework, and legacy infrastructure to modern replacements. Resulting in more stable, faster development, and reduced infrastructure costs.
- Built a multi-tenant dashboard in React for large enterprise clients.
- Designed and built initial Laravel API and Angular UI for TenFour an emergency check-in tool for teams.
- Moved the dev team to a collaborative agile dev process. Resulting in more predictable releases, and closer integration with product and design.

PHP, Laravel, Kohana, Javascript, React, AngularJS, Python, MySQL, RabbitMQ, Ansible, Terraform.

Ushahidi – Senior Developer

2012 - 2015, Remote

I joined Ushahidi in 2012 to lead development of client projects. In 2014 I led development of a new iteration of Ushahidi software.

- Led development of Ushahidi's open-source crowdsourcing tool.
- Launched SaaS edition of Ushahidi based on our open-source product.
- Technical contact and lead developer on client projects.
- Working within and improving an existing legacy code base over time.
- Deployed, managed and monitored infrastructure for client projects.
- Leading response and mitigation of security issues.

PHP, Laravel, Kohana, Javascript, AngularJS, Python, MySQL, RabbitMQ, Ansible.

Torchbox - Drupal Web Developer

2010 - 2011. Oxford, UK

Torchbox is a digital agency building websites and application for people trying to make the world a better place.

- Developed complex Drupal based sites for charities and nonprofits.
- Scaling and optimising complex Drupal sites through a combination of static caching (with varnish and nginx) and improved app level caching.
- Building tools for fast, standardised development and deployment.

PHP, Drupal, Javascript, Python, MySQL, Sass, HTML, CSS.

Greenpeace New Zealand – Web Developer

2009 - 2010. Auckland, NZ

Joined Greenpeace NZ in 2009 as their first full time developer, initially focussed on supporting a large online campaign around climate change.

- Developed multiple web applications and websites.
- Managing websites and social media feeds during high traffic live events.
- Deployed and optimized online fundraising tools for increased donations.
- Security testing and fixes on legacy web apps.

PHP, Drupal, Silverstripe, Javascript, HTML, CSS, MySQL, PostgreSQL.

Freelance – Web Developer

2002 - 2009

Worked as a freelance web developer part time while studying and then full time for a year. Developed a range of websites and applications for small businesses.

PHP, Silverstripe, Javascript, HTML + CSS.

Education

University of Auckland – Bachelor of Engineering (Computer Systems)

Graduated 2009